<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-09-12T11:50:27.901Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-09-12T11:50:27.901Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[200 Universities Just Launched 850+ Free Online Courses. Here’s the Full List.]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/new-online-courses/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/new-online-courses/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-10T10:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you haven’t heard, universities around the world are offering their courses online for free (or at least, partially free). These courses are collectively called MOOCs or Massive Open Online Courses. [https://www.classcentral.com/help/moocs] In the past ten years, ~1000 universities have created around tens of thousands of MOOCs. I’ve been keeping]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dhawal Shah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro to Deno – Guide for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/intro-to-deno/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/intro-to-deno/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T22:50:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is Deno? Deno is a new JavaScript runtime. It was built by Ryan Dahl, the creator of Node.js.  Dahl had a few things that he regretted doing with Node and wanted to build a runtime that could solve those issues. Deno, like Node, is built on the V8]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Barrow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Push Local Branch to Remote – How to Publish a New Branch in Git]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/git-push-local-branch-to-remote-how-to-publish-a-new-branch-in-git/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/git-push-local-branch-to-remote-how-to-publish-a-new-branch-in-git/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T20:36:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Git branches let you add new features without tampering with the live version of your projects. And if you work in a team, different developers might have unique branches they work on. In the long run, you'll have to push those independent branches to a remote server. For example, GitHub,]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kolade Chris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node Version Manager – nvm Install Guide]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/node-version-manager-nvm-install-guide/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/node-version-manager-nvm-install-guide/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T18:23:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I'll explain how you can install NVM, or Node Version Manager, on Windows, Linux, and Mac. What is NVM? Node Version Manager (NVM), as the name implies, is a tool for managing Node versions on your device. Different projects on your device may be using different versions]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dillion Megida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Made a Pure CSS Puzzle Game]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372952</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-i-made-a-pure-css-puzzle-game/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T13:21:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently discovered the joy of creating CSS-only games. It’s always fascinating how HTML and CSS are capable of handling the logic of an entire online game, so I had to try it! Such games usually rely on the ol’ …
How I Made a Pure CSS Puzzle Game originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Formula To Rule Them All: The ROI Of A Design System]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/formula-roi-design-system/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/formula-roi-design-system/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-09T08:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Design systems are a crucial success factor for digital businesses, and virtually every major player works with one. Still, they can sometimes be hard to sell to management. Here’s a ready-to-use formula to calculate the ROI of any design system.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Maximilian Speicher &amp; Guido Baena Wehrmann)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Line Charts Tutorial – How to Create a Line Graph in JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-line-charts-in-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-make-line-charts-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T19:58:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data visualization is a vast field with so many different types of charts [https://datavizcatalogue.com/] to learn and create.  But there are several basic, evergreen graphs that every data designer and web developer dealing with analytics should know how to build.  One of them is a Line Chart (or]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shachee Swadia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python .split() – Splitting a String in Python]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-split-a-string-in-python/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-split-a-string-in-python/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T17:22:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, you will learn how to split a string in Python. Firstly, I'll introduce you to the syntax of the .split() method. After that, you will see how to use the .split() method with and without arguments, using code examples along the way. Here is what we will]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dionysia Lemonaki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Improve Machine Learning Code Quality with Scikit-learn Pipeline and ColumnTransformer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-pipeline/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/machine-learning-pipeline/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T16:31:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you're working on a machine learning project, the most tedious steps are often data cleaning and preprocessing. Especially when you're working in a Jupyter Notebook, running code in many cells can be confusing. The Scikit-learn library has tools called Pipeline and ColumnTransformer that can really make your life easier.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yannawut Kimnaruk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use IndexedDB – Database Guide for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-indexeddb-works-for-beginners/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-indexeddb-works-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T16:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The modern browser has given us a number of options when it comes to storing data on the client-side. Aside from storing data, browser databases allow us to retrieve that data.  Based on your application's needs, you can choose from the different browser storage options out there to enhance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Yakubu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Debug Dockerized .NET Core Apps in VS Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-debug-dockerized-net-core-apps-in-vs-code/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-debug-dockerized-net-core-apps-in-vs-code/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T15:34:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I recently switched to VS Code for development of a dockerized .NET core app. But I then realized that there weren't many up-to-date articles about debugging dockerized .NET core applications in VS Code. Source: GIPHYSo, here I am, writing this article. I hope that it'll help others like myself in]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haseeb Ahmed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Excel Tutorial – How to Create Formulas and Functions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-microsoft-excel-formulas-and-functions/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-microsoft-excel-formulas-and-functions/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T15:17:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spreadsheets aren't merely for arranging data into rows and columns. Most of the time, you use them for data analysis as well.  Microsoft Excel is one of the most widely used spreadsheet applications, especially in finance and accounting. This is partly because of its easy UI and unmatched depth]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benny Ifeanyi Iheagwara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s New With Forms in 2022?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372979</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/whats-new-with-forms-in-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T13:12:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Browsers are constantly adding new HTML, JavaScript and CSS features. Here are some useful additions to working with forms that you might have missed…
requestSubmit()
Safari 16 will be the final browser to add support for requestSubmit.
Before we …
What’s New With Forms in 2022? originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UX Checklists For Interface Designers]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/ux-checklists-for-interface-designers/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/ux-checklists-for-interface-designers/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-08T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UX checklists with best design practices, accessibility guidelines, design system checklist, tables UX checklist, UX research methods, form design UX and flowcharts.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overlapping Bar Charts]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372968</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/overlapping-bar-charts/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-07T13:46:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the name suggests, overlapping charts visualize two different sets of data in a single diagram. The idea is that the overlapping bars allow us to compare data, say, year-over-year. They are also useful for things like tracking progress for …
Overlapping Bar Charts originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saleh Mubashar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Realities And Myths Of Contrast And Color]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/realities-myths-contrast-color/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/realities-myths-contrast-color/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Andrew Somers, a 35-year veteran of the Hollywood film and television industry, shares his experience about the hard-fought battles and lessons learned designing for illuminated presentations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Andrew Somers)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacking CSS Animation State and Playback Time]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372850</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/hacking-css-animation-state-and-playback-time/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T18:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSS-only Wolfenstein is a little project that I made a few weeks ago. It was an experiment with CSS 3D transformations and animations.
Inspired by the FPS demo and another Wolfenstein CodePen, I decided to build my own version. …
Hacking CSS Animation State and Playback Time originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lu Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 52 With Yiying Lu: How Do You Become An NFT Artist?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/smashing-podcast-episode-52/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/smashing-podcast-episode-52/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we ask how do you go from running a creative studio to designing NFTs. Vitaly talks to artist Yiying Lu to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flutter For Front-End Web Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372853</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/flutter-for-front-end-web-developers/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T20:10:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I started as a front-end web developer and then became a Flutter developer. I think there were some concepts that helped me adopt Flutter easier. There were also some new concepts that were different.
In this article, I want to …
Flutter For Front-End Web Developers originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Obumuneme Nwabude</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Understanding Privacy, A New Smashing Book By Heather Burns]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/understanding-privacy-pre-release/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/understanding-privacy-pre-release/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-05T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meet “Understanding Privacy”, our upcoming book on what data privacy is really about beyond scary headlines. Approx. 350 pages. eBook available in October, print shipping in November.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Accessibility And Usability Journey Of Drupal’s Primary Navigation]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/accessibility-usability-drupal-primary-navigation/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/accessibility-usability-drupal-primary-navigation/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-02T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Mike Herchel covers Drupal’s new default theme, Olivero, which is usable, accessible, robust, and beautiful and will help you improve websites’ navigation systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mike Herchel)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Behind the CSScenes, September 2022]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=373126</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/behind-the-csscenes-sept2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T20:06:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those of you who have been reading CSS-Tricks for a while may remember that we used to publish a little thing we called CSS-Tricks Chronicles. Our friend Chris Coyier would write up a reflection from the past couple of …
Behind the CSScenes, September 2022 originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haley Mills</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Brief Introduction to JAWS, NVDA, and VoiceOver]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372855</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/comparing-jaws-nvda-and-voiceover/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T17:47:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A screen reader is an important accessibility tool for people with no or limited vision. People who are blind or those with low vision can use a screen reader to navigate the computer. Screen readers will read contents on the …
A Brief Introduction to JAWS, NVDA, and VoiceOver originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ilknur Eren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[iShadeed’s Container Queries Lab]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=373087</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/ishadeeds-container-queries-lab/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T14:29:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahmad Shadeed got an early jump on container queries and has a growing collection of examples based on everyday patterns.
And, if you missed it, his latest post on container queries does a wonderful job covering how they work since …
iShadeed’s Container Queries Lab originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Databases For Front-End Developers: The Concepts Under The Hood (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/databases-frontend-developers-concepts-under-hood/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/databases-frontend-developers-concepts-under-hood/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the second part of “Databases For Front-End Developers” series, Atila Fassina explores concepts to equip you to have your own opinions about which kinds of databases suit your specific needs.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Atila Fassina)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Useful JavaScript Data Grid Libraries]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/useful-javascript-data-grid-libraries/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/09/useful-javascript-data-grid-libraries/"/>
        <updated>2022-09-01T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Zara Cooper provides a rundown of some popular data grid libraries that would be a great addition to any data-heavy application and shares recommendations on what factors to consider when choosing a suitable data grid library.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Zara Cooper)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finding The Balance (September 2022 Desktop Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-september-2022/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-september-2022/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-31T08:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s welcome September with some fresh desktop wallpapers. Designed by artists and designers from across the globe, they come in versions with and without a calendar for the month. Enjoy!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpolating Numeric CSS Variables]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372839</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/interpolating-numeric-css-variables/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T13:17:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We can make variables in CSS pretty easily:
:root {
  --scale: 1;
}
And we can declare them on any element:
.thing {
  transform: scale(var(--scale));
}
Even better for an example like this is applying the variable on a user …
Interpolating Numeric CSS Variables originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Improve And Measure Your Progress Learning Web Design]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/improve-measure-progress-learning-web-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/improve-measure-progress-learning-web-design/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-30T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever felt overwhelmed by the number of things you need to learn? Today, we look at how [Uxcel](https://uxcel.com/) eases this transition and approaches actively learning new skills to take our careers to the next level.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Shane Hudson)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes A Great Toggle Button? (Case Study, Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/toggle-button-case-study-part-2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/toggle-button-case-study-part-2/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-29T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The problem of how to design an effective toggle button that shows the selected option clearly is a long-term open question among UI/UX designers. In this second part, Eduard Kuric explains a complex list of visual cues used by toggle buttons to communicate which of their options is active.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eduard Kuric)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Grid Named Areas to Visualize (and Reference) Your Layout]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372634</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-grid-named-areas-to-visualize-and-reference-your-layout/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-26T13:44:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whenever we build simple or complex layouts using CSS Grid, we’re usually positioning items with line numbers. Grid layouts contain grid lines that are automatically indexed with positive and negative line numbers (that is unless we explicitly name them). …
Using Grid Named Areas to Visualize (and Reference) Your Layout originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Preethi Selvam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing Better Error Messages UX]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/error-messages-ux-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/error-messages-ux-design/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-25T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Error messages need to be easy to spot, but they also need to be helpful. Let’s explore when error messages should live above input fields and why toast error messages are usually not a very good idea.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not Sure How to WordPress Anymore?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372616</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/not-sure-how-to-wordpress-anymore/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-25T14:34:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neither do I! And that’s probably because there’s a lot happening in WordPress-land. The evolution towards full-site editing (FSE) introduces frequent changes to the way we build themes and plugins, and at such break-neck speed that the documentation itself is …
Not Sure How to WordPress Anymore? originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Video Streaming With imgix]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/better-video-streaming-with-imgix/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/better-video-streaming-with-imgix/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-25T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you need to deliver a large number of images and videos, a solution like [imgix](https://imgix.com/?utm_medium=banner&utm_source=smashingmag&utm_campaign=video-api-smashingmag-article-2022-08) can optimize and process both types of assets without you having to build it from the ground up or cobble together different solutions. Let’s take a closer look at how.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Doug Sillars)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using CSS Cascade Layers to Manage Custom Styles in a Tailwind Project]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372576</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/using-css-cascade-layers-to-manage-custom-styles-in-a-tailwind-project/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-24T13:11:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If a utility class only does one thing, chances are you don’t want it to be overridden by any styles coming from elsewhere. One approach is to use !important to be 100% certain the style will be applied, regardless of …
Using CSS Cascade Layers to Manage Custom Styles in a Tailwind Project originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ollie Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Removing jQuery from GOV.UK]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372485</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/removing-jquery-from-gov-uk/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-23T13:04:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GOV.UK team recently published “How and why we removed jQuery from GOV.UK“. This was an insightful look at how an organization can assess its tooling and whether something is still the best tool for the job. This …
Removing jQuery from GOV.UK originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bradley Kouchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 51 With Ben Callahan: What’s The Value Of A Design System?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/smashing-podcast-episode-51/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/smashing-podcast-episode-51/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-23T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this episode of the Smashing Podcast, we ask how you can prove the value of a Design System and how you can pitch it effectively to stakeholders. Vitaly talks to Ben Callahan to find out more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Grid and Custom Shapes, Part 2]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372396</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/css-grid-and-custom-shapes-part-2/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-22T14:08:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, so the last time we checked in, we were using CSS Grid and combining them with CSS clip-path and mask techniques to create grids with fancy shapes.
Here’s just one of the fantastic grids we made together:
CodePen…
CSS Grid and Custom Shapes, Part 2 originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Temani Afif</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Makes A Great Toggle Button? (Case Study, Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/toggle-button-case-study-part-1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/toggle-button-case-study-part-1/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-22T09:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this first part of a two-part article, Eduard Kuric analyzes the characteristics of effective toggle buttons that make it error-proof and prevent confusion and frustration of users.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Eduard Kuric)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing A Reset Password Feature With Next.js Dynamic Routes]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/implementing-reset-password-feature-nextjs-dynamic-routes/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/implementing-reset-password-feature-nextjs-dynamic-routes/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most users tend to forget their passwords, so create experiences that will always be valuable for people when they use your products. In this article, we’ll discuss how to implement a password-reset feature with Next.js dynamic routes while prioritizing the UX.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Caleb Olojo)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Do You Use CSS Columns?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=372539</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/when-do-you-use-css-columns/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-18T13:24:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[That ain’t rhetorical: I’m really interested in finding great use cases for CSS multi-column layouts.
The answer seems straightforward. Use columns when you want to split any content into columns, right? Here is generally the sort of example you’ll find …
When Do You Use CSS Columns? originally published on CSS-Tricks, which is part of the DigitalOcean family. You should get the newsletter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Geoff Graham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Introduction To Context Propagation In JavaScript]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/react-context-propagation-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/react-context-propagation-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-18T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[React popularized context-propagation within applications with the context API. Evyatar Alush brings a brief intro to context propagation in JavaScript and how you can build React Context yourself.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Evyatar Alush)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing A Better Back Button UX]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/back-button-ux-design/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/back-button-ux-design/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-16T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the “Back” button, users often get confused and frustrated. How to design a better back button UX and where to put those “Back” buttons in our interfaces.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Vitaly Friedman)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything Developers Must Know About Figma]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/everything-developers-must-know-about-figma/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2022/08/everything-developers-must-know-about-figma/"/>
        <updated>2022-08-15T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christine highlights some of Figma’s features and possibilities to help you build a design that aligns with code as much as needed and improve your team work.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Christine Vallaure)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>